

RESUME OBJECTIVE

A highly motivated and customer-oriented computer technician with 18 years of experience and a trainee software developer with 4 months of experience in Python, HTML, CSS, React, and SQL seeking a challenging position that allows me to utilize my skills and knowledge to deliver innovative solutions for clients.

EXPERIENCE

COMPUTER TECHNICIAN

Home Service / April 2021 - Present

- Diagnosed and resolved hardware and software issues for both PC and Laptops.
- Provided technical support to customers in-person, via email and phone.
- Installed, configured and maintained network devices such as routers, switches, and firewalls.
- Performed system backups and data recovery procedures.
- · Trained and mentored junior technicians.

JUNIOR PYTHON DEVELOPER

Klever 4 Solutions / November 2020 - March 2021

- Developed and maintained various applications using python and related technologies.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, develop and deploy software solutions.
- Troubleshot and resolved technical issues in a timely manner.
- Contributed to the improvement of development processes and methodologies.

CONTACTS

Email:

mauriciofrias22@gmail.com

Phone: 314 894 8363 Address: Barrio Alcibia, Urb. Villa Liliana Torre 8

Apto 704

SOCIAL MEDIA

f mauricio.j.ortiz

mauriciofrias22

mauricio-javier-friasortiz-82251677

mauriciofrias22

PERSONAL SKILLS

Problem Solving

Adaptability

Assertive

Communication

Creativity

Empathy

Responsibility

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Customer Service

Teamwork

English

Scrum

Git



EXPERIENCE

LIMO SERVICE DRIVER

Luxury Rentals / March 2018 - October 2019

- Safely transport of clients from one location to another in a comfortable and stylish manner.
- Perform routine inspections to make sure that the limo is clean, well
 maintained, and fully stocked with necessary amenities such as
 drinks and snacks.
- Anticipate and respond to the client needs.
- Plan the most efficient route to take based on traffic conditions, weather, and other factors.
- Ensure the safety and security of the clients while they are in transit.

COMPUTER TECHNICIAN

Home Service / April 2016 - February 2018

- Diagnosed and resolved hardware and software issues for both PC and Laptops.
- Provided technical support to customers in-person, via email and phone.
- Installed, configured and maintained network devices such as routers, switches, and firewalls.
- Performed system backups and data recovery procedures.
- Trained and mentored junior technicians.

CONTACTS

Email:

mauriciofrias22@gmail.com

Phone: 314 894 8363 Address: Barrio Alcibia, Urb. Villa Liliana Torre 8

Apto 704

mauricio.j.ortiz

mauriciofrias22

mauricio-javier-friasortiz-82251677

mauriciofrias22

PERSONAL SKILLS

Problem Solving

Adaptability

Assertive

Communication

Creativity

Empathy

Responsibility

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Customer Service

Teamwork

English

Scrum

Git



EXPERIENCE

BILINGUAL COUNTER ASSISTANT

Avis Car Rental / March 2015 - April 2016

- Provide excellent service to the customers, addressing their needs and concerns, and ensuring a positive experience with the company.
- Assist customers with making reservations, answering questions about rental rates, and providing information about the rental process.
- Perform thorough inspections to vehicles before renting them to minimize any issues or concerns that customers may have during their rental period.
- Pickup and drop-off vehicles on customers locations when needed.
- Address any customer complaints or concerns and provide prompt and effective solutions. Additionally, to gather feedback from customers to continuously improve the customer experience.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDAD DEL NORTE

Misiontic 2022 Program / December 2021

• Diploma of programming skills with emphasis on web development.

UNIVERSIDAD DEL NORTE

Misiontic 2022 Program / December 2021

 Programming fundamentals, basic programming and software development courses.

CONTACTS

Email:

mauriciofrias22@gmail.com

Phone: 314 894 8363 Address: Barrio Alcibia, Urb. Villa Liliana Torre 8

Apto 704

mauricio.j.ortiz

mauriciofrias22

mauricio-javier-friasortiz-82251677

mauriciofrias22

PERSONAL SKILLS

Problem Solving

Adaptability

Assertive

Communication

Creativity

Empathy

Responsibility

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Customer Service

Teamwork

English

Scrum

Git



EDUCATION

UDEMY

Virtual platform / November 2020

- Linear data structures course.
- Code foundations course.
- Learn how to code course.
- Python developer course.

BERLITZ

I speak Program / December 2012

· Berlitz proficiency test.

SENA

T / May 2004

Basic accounting course.

UNITEP

Computer Maintenance / November 2002

• Assembly, maintenance, repair and computer configuration.

CENTRO CULTURAL COLOMBO AMERICANO OF CARTAGENA

English Language / August 2002

English proficiency.

CONTACTS

Email:

mauriciofrias22@gmail.com

Phone: 314 894 8363 Address: Barrio Alcibia, Urb. Villa Liliana Torre 8

Apto 704

mauricio.j.ortiz

mauriciofrias22

mauricio-javier-friasortiz-82251677

mauriciofrias22

PERSONAL SKILLS

Problem Solving

Adaptability

Assertive

Communication

Creativity

Empathy

Responsibility

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Customer Service

Teamwork

English

Scrum

Git